JULIO CASTRO

Senior Software Engineer

+41 76 513 18 64 l julio.castro.dev@gmail.com l linkedin.com/in/juliocastrodev

SUMMARY

Extensive experience in software engineering from startup to large corporate levels. Proven success leading teams in various technologies including Angular, React, Nodejs or Spring Boot, resulting in highly performing, harmonious and cohesive teams with deep technical and business knowledge. Succeeded in applying mathematical and scientific skills to drive and clarify intricate and complex business challenges, resulting in bigger, better and faster achievements.

SKILLS

- Languages: Typescript, Java, Python, HTML/CSS, Javascript, SQL.
- Technologies: Angular, React, Spring Boot, Nodejs, Nextjs, Cypress.
- Other: Domain Driven Design, Clean Arguitecture, Modern Reactivity.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at We Feed Raw, a US pet food start up I Acid Tango

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

- Led, built and maintained the backend and most of the entire infrastructure, achieved a successful migration and launch, returning a +50% increase in users and also new project signings and extensions with the customer.
- Migrated the complex pet feeding algorithm to an efficient and easy to read and extend solution, to the point that it was reused in another similar product for the UK.
- Contributed and collaborated closely with the frontend team, achieving record delivery performance in the company, even reaching to release features in production within minutes.
- Actively participated and led weekly company conferences sharing and teaching on a multitude of topics, achieving direct positive impact on 5+ different projects.
- <u>Skills:</u> TypeScript, React, Nextjs, Domain Driven Design, Nodejs, Nestjs, PostgreSQL, AWS, GitHub Actions, Simplified Scrum, Trello, Figma.

Senior Software Engineer at We Feed Raw, a US pet food start up I Acid Tango

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

- Led, built and maintained the backend and most of the entire infrastructure, achieved a successful migration and launch, returning a +50% increase in users and also new project signings and extensions with the customer.
- Migrated the complex pet feeding algorithm to an efficient and easy to read and extend solution, to the point that it was reused in another similar product for the UK.

- Contributed and collaborated closely with the frontend team, achieving record delivery performance in the company, even reaching to release features in production within minutes.
- Actively participated and led weekly company conferences sharing and teaching on a multitude of topics, achieving direct positive impact on 5+ different projects.
- <u>Skills:</u> TypeScript, React, Nextjs, Domain Driven Design, Nodejs, Nestjs, PostgreSQL, AWS, GitHub Actions, Simplified Scrum, Trello, Figma.

Frontend Developer at Openbank, Satander's digital bank I Fabrik

Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

- Led the upgrade of the microfrontend dedicated to bank transfers, managed to remove thousands of lines of legacy code, reducing related story point estimates by 80%.
- Became the go-to person for technical questions from both business and development.
- Skills: TypeScript, React, Microfrontends, Redux, Bitbucket, Scrum, Jira, Figma.

Backend Developer at Santander Payment Hub I Fabrik

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

- Integrated microservices in a macroscopic project of 300+ engineers focused on Santander's international payment system, achieving on-time goals with 5+ constraints while maintaining business requirements and high quality standards.
- Implemented deployment support tool reducing human errors by 80%.
- Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Kafka, Bitbucket, Microsoft Azure, Scrum, Pivotal Tracker.

Frontend Developer at Santander Innovation Lab I Fabrik

Feb 2020 - Jul 2020

- Participated in development tasks for a hybrid mobile application for Santander UK, outstanding with 50% above average delivery performance.
- Implemented the most important algorithm for the user experience: the credit card refresh logic, a key feature for business and development. Task estimated to be completed in one week and completed in one day, being afterwards a simpler, more robust and efficient solution.
- Skills: TypeScript, Angular, Ionic, GitLab, Scrum, Jira, Figma.

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Automated the end to end regression tests of 4 hybrid mobile applications focused on the banking sector, resulting in a reduction from 2 weeks of manual work to 10 minutes of automatic execution, a milestone achieved for the first time in the team and in the whole company.
- Obtained the opportunity to work in the development team due to great performance, business knowledge and problem solving skills.
- Skills: Java, Selenium, Appium, GitLab, Scrum, Jira.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science from the Polytechnic University of Madrid

2017 - 2021

- Achieved an average score of 9/10.
- Awarded every year and throughout all 4 years with the recognition of academic excellence on behalf of the city of Madrid.

LANGUAGES

• English: C1.

• German: A2 - B1.

Spanish: Native.